it has been a long time
since i ventured beyond my county i took
a needed trip to the coast to visit my
father
i spent some of my childhood here and it
is a place full of memories
consequently i found myself reflecting
on my life and how
far i've come and being satisfied with
what i have
[Music]
so
as the daughter of a military man i
traveled a lot as a child
having grown up in many parts of the u.s
cuba
puerto rico italy and ireland
i was always moving and while i wouldn't
trade my childhood for the world
i also yearned for a stable community
friendships that didn't have to be long
distance
and a closer connection to a specific
place i could call home now i
barely venture out of my county much
less my state
while there are lands i still plan to
see someday i'm content to explore my
own home
discovering new things and learning
about the environment i live in staying
put has given me a chance to observe the
seasons in one place
and notice the changes from year to year
[Music]
traveling is wonderful but it doesn't
always need to involve far away places
sometimes it's simply an exploration of
one's local area
or if you are in a particularly
adventurous mood an exploration of your
own
spirit there's so much to discover about
oneself
that is the one journey that is never
over and is always available to take
external experiences are fleeting but
your inner self
is the one that you carry with you
wherever you go
and yet oftentimes it is forgotten in
the midst of
busyness
[Music]
while exciting new experiences can be
life-changing and memorable
it is the little more ordinary details
that take up the majority of our
time and it is often the part of the
story that only you truly know
in a way that gives us power to make it
whatever we wish it to be
who we truly are is not always seen by
other people
it is also our thoughts our ideas and
feelings
we can show each other where we've
traveled and what we've achieved
it is much harder to communicate who we
are on the inside
and yet that is the only thing we carry
with us all the time
i believe we can be very well traveled
without physically going anywhere
we can explore our imaginations our
questions
our spiritual perspectives
[Music]
do
if you are unable to travel do not feel
as if you are
missing out you can always choose to go
on a journey simply of a different kind
and it is no less meaningful
[Music]
you